GAURAV KAPOOR

Mobile: 9923700753 gaurav_capur@yahoo.co.in

Career Summary

Human Resource professional offering 17+ years of experience including 14.5 years in Human Resource, 3 years in Business Operations Support. Rich and insightful experience in leading large HR teams in IT and Operations across a variety of industry domains in Services and GIC organizations.

HR Operations / HR Shared Services: setup framework for HR policies / processes and systems, HR MIS & analytics, Hire to Retire, Payroll & HR compliances, Attendance management, Employee Benefits (flexi benefits / insurance / reimbursements), Employee Personal record management, HR audit coordination, HR Invoicing and Vendor management

<u>Comp & Ben</u>: skilled in leading Organization's Compensation & Benefits review, Executive compensation, pay to performance, market survey & analysis, competency & job mapping, change management

<u>Global Mobility</u>: Expats and repatriates' compensation, payroll and statutory compliances management, Supervise Hire to Retire across entities, managing compliances related to deputation and repatriation

<u>HR Digitalization (Automation)</u>: Successfully led and functionally designed HR shared services system automation & digitalization projects across SuccessFactors, PeopleSoft HRMS and Oracle HRMS

Core Competencies

HR Operations || HR Shared Services || Comp & Ben || Global Mobility || HR Digitalization || Talent Acquisition || Change Management || HR Compliances || Vendor Management || Process and Systems driven

HR Career



Professional Experience

Allstate Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

Pune, Maharashtra

Associate Manager – HR Operations (HR Shared Services)

Jan 2018 - till date

- Spearheading the India HR Operations set-up (Pune & Bangalore) with span of 5000 employees across IT and ITES verticals
- Lead India HR operations for ASPL including Background verification, On-boarding, Orientation, Payroll processing, Off-boarding, HR MIS & Analytics, Employee record management, attendance management, vendor management, HR audits & HR Invoicing
- Leading transformation of India HR operations into a full service HRSS setup by incorporating varied HR service offerings and ensuring continuous improvement to cater business needs
- Introduced HR systems for background verification, payroll, Onboarding, time & attendance and offboarding
- Strategic alignment of policies, processes & systems to ensure seamless employee experience within defined service levels
- Transformation of manual & repetitive task into Automated and Digitalized environment in the role of HR functional consultant
- Managing HR Operations team of 09 resources (FTE's & Contractors) across Pune and Bangalore

Tech Mahindra Ltd.

Pune, Maharashtra

Manager – Associates Services (HR Shared Services)

May 2015 – Jan 2018

- Spearheading HR Invoicing, Employee Benefits, HR Compliances and Query management set-up (Pune & Hyderabad) with span of 7500 employees of TechM's IT vertical with global collaboration spanning across India, USA and UK geography
- Liaised with employees and HRBP's across India, USA and UK to effectively manage the shared services activities
- Payroll Management collation of HR inputs related to New Hire Employee data, allowances, retention bonus, full and final settlement
- Attendance & Leave Management
- Employee benefits administration regards to medical insurance for employees on deputation & repatriation
- Statutory compliance administration related to provident fund & ESIC, labour welfare fund, Shops & Establishment Act and CLRA
- Query Management

Specialist Compensation & Benefits

Jan 2012 – Apr 2015

- Compensation administration for Leadership employees across India, USA and UK
- Performance pay management including variable pay, sales incentives, performance bonus, quarterly reviews to track performance against targets, query handling
- Assist policy team with inputs regards to designing performance pay related policies
- Payroll management

Hutchison Global Services Pvt. Ltd

Pune, Maharashtra

1) Assistant Manager – Compensation & Benefits

Sep 2010 - Jan 2012

- Compensation management including Incentive Payout
- Human Resource Information System (HRIS)
- Budgeting & Provisions
- Benefits management
- Onboarding & Separation
- Personal file management

2) Assistant Manager – Recruitment

Sep 2007 - Aug 2010

- Performance Analysis
- Vendor Management
- Direct Channel Sourcing
- Process adherence & compliance
- Temp Staff Management

IBM Daksh Business Process Services Pvt. Ltd.

Pune, Maharashtra

Lead – Resourcing

Oct 2005 - Sep 2007

- Forecasting trends
- Scheduling & Rostering
- Performance Analysis
- Vendor Management

WNS Global Services

Pune, Maharashtra

Senior Executive – Quality & MIS May 2004 -Oct 2005 Senior Customer Service Executive Nov 2003 -Apr 2004

Msource India

Pune, Maharashtra

Customer Service Executive Oct 2002 -Nov 2003

Datalink Systems Services

Pune, Maharashtra

Team Lead Feb 2002 -Sept 2002

Education & Training

PG Diploma in Advance Computing 2002
Bachelor of Labour Law 1999
Bachelor of Commerce 1996

Personal Details

Date of birth:

Locality/City:

11 March 1975
Dhanori, Pune